<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../XMLSchema/TestCase.xsl"?>
<TestCase id="TLS_B2_GP_10" xmlns="http://bsi.bund.de/TR03116" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://bsi.bund.de/TR03116 ../../../XMLSchema/TR03116.xsd">
	<Title>Test case TLS_B2_GP_10</Title>
	<Version>1.1</Version>
	<Purpose>This positive test evaluates the ability of the DUT to select a stronger cipher suite given a choice.</Purpose>
	<Profile>TLS_SERVER</Profile>
	<Profile>CLIENT_CERT</Profile>
	<Profile>INTERIM_SUITES_SRV</Profile>
	<Profile>TLS_1.2</Profile>
	<Reference>RFC 5246</Reference>
	<Precondition>DUT services are online without any known disturbances.</Precondition>
	<Precondition>The DUT is accepting TLS connections.</Precondition>

	<TestStep>
		<Command>
			<Text>The tester connects to the DUT.</Text>
		</Command>
		<Description>The TLS ClientHello offers the TLS version [TLS_VERSION].</Description>
		<Description>The TLS ClientHello offers cipher suites which are supported according to the ICS, however in the reverted order. This means that the less preferable cipher suite is put at the beginning of the list, while the most preferable is put at the end of the list.</Description>
		<Description>In case the cipher suite is based on ECC, the TLS ClientHello offers valid elliptic curves in the appropriate extension according to the ICS.</Description>
		<Description>The presence of the signature_algorithms extension depends on the used TLS version. In case it is sent, all algorithms that are supported according to the ICS are listed.</Description>
		<Description>The TLS ClientHello does not contain further extensions which are not required to conduct the TLS handshake.</Description>
		<ExpectedResult>
			<Text>The DUT accepts the ClientHello.</Text>
		</ExpectedResult>
		<ExpectedResult>
			<Text>The DUT ignores the order of the cipher suites in the client hello and does not select any interim cipher suite from the beginning of the list. Instead one of the recommended cipher suites from the end of the list is selected.</Text>
		</ExpectedResult>
		<ExpectedResult>
			<Text>It requests client authentication.</Text>
		</ExpectedResult>
	</TestStep>
	<TestStep>
		<Command>
			<Text>The TLS client supplies the valid certificate chain [CERT_DEFAULT_CLIENT].</Text>
		</Command>	
		<ExpectedResult>
			<Text>The TLS protocol is executed without errors and the channel is established.</Text>
		</ExpectedResult>
	</TestStep>
</TestCase>
